hello and welcome to the 22nd tutorial
on how to program in gript 2 let's make
a new weapon and call it whatever you
want I already have this weapon added to
me so whatever I already have that done
so add client side and do function
Onkey pressed parenthesis brackets Now
function Onkey press is a pre-built
function like a lot of the other ones
we've learned and what it does is
it will when you press a key it'll do
stuff now there are three parameters in
Onkey pressed one comma 2 comma 3 we'll
name them anything we want but let's
name the first one key
code second one key name the third one
scan
code the first parentheses which in our
condition is named key code stands for
the number of the button you're pressing
such as a would be
65 shift would be 160 and so on every
number or button on your keyboard has a
number to
it now key name is just the name of the
key such as a would be a b would be B J
would be J shift wouldn't have one and
so wouldn't control so you can't use
those two buttons when using key name
scan code is very similar to key code
because all the numbers have a I mean
all the buttons have a number however it
is based on the position of the key keys
and have and if you have a keyboard that
like a weird keyboard that has keys in
different
positions then it's going to get things
done differently so you would just want
to use key code instead of scan
code okay now in the in the thing let's
add if key code is equal to
65 then put player. chat equal to key
code oh never
mind um what is equal
to you have pressed
a apply it when we press a it says you
have pressed a now let's say we don't
know the value of a certain key like
control or or F3 or something like that
well what we can do is put player do
chat is equal to key
code click apply when we press a it's
going to say 65 shift will say 160
control say 162 F3 will open up
something and it'll say
114 so that's what key code does we can
also replace this with key name or scan
code which are just the which or
whatever whatever you have named those
three
variables C apply and key name will work
except for shift and control and
everything else that doesn't have a key
name so that concludes the tutorial on
on key pressed and there's one more
thing I want to show you let's make a
new
function
on go to you can name this anything you
want I'm just naming it go to you don't
even have to
name it that just name it whatever you
want but let's go here in the first
function Onkey pressed and add go to
then parenthesis and semicolon so you
can guess what this is going to do
whenever you press any key on the
keyboard no matter what you press it's
going to run this command and go to this
function and do absolutely nothing but
we're going to change that let's say you
want to send over a variable to this
function like you have a variable called
temp. high and it's equal
to
something well we can send that over
just put just put in the name of the
variable into the parentheses on the fun
command that's going to go to the
function and in the function in these
parentheses add any the variable of
anything you want like
temp. Hello it can be anything because
it's not going to to be it doesn't have
to be the name of what you're
sending and then let's put player. chat
equals temp. hello oh or just hello
because it's temp. variable so what this
is doing is we're creating a temp.
variable and because we know it's going
to be deleted as soon as the function
ends we want to send it over to a
different function so we're going to
create a command that's going to go to a
different function and we're bringing
along this variable too over here as
soon as it goes over here it's going to
replace the name of the variable with
this name it's going to keep the same
value so H high is going to so hello is
still going to be equal to something but
it's going to have a different
name and that's why when we it's going
to that's why when we say when it says
player. chat equal to hello it's making
equal to temp. high so I hope you
understand
that we can also do this we can delete
this and put
in key
code and it's going to send over
whatever we
press remember this will only work with
temp. variables because this. variables
are don't get deleted as the function
ends so there's no need to move them
over to a different function now let's
say you want to move over the this.
variables to a different NPC well in
that case then well we're not going to
get into it yet but in that case this
will work so anyway that concludes this
tutorial and I hope you understand how
to use enke pressed and understand how
to send over variables to other
functions so bye